<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: javascript | You've got a lot of Gal]]></title>
  <link href="http://galori.github.com/blog/categories/javascript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://galori.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-02T14:27:52-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://galori.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Gal Steinitz]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Firebug Lite on an iPad]]></title>
    <link href="http://galori.github.com/blog/2013/07/22/firebug-lite-on-an-ipad/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-22T16:42:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://galori.github.com/blog/2013/07/22/firebug-lite-on-an-ipad</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Firebug Lite works really well on an iPad. If you want a quick way to inspect any web page, here is how you install the Firebug Lite bookmarklet on mobile Safari on an iPad. (Or for that matter, any other mobile device)</p>

<!--more-->


<ol>
<li>Bookmark this page. (Yes, THIS page. Thats the only way to create a new bookmark. Don't worry we're going to change it in the next step)</li></li>
<li>Copy the bookmarklet javascript code in the text area below:
<textarea style='width: 665px; height: 43px; display: block;'>javascript:(function(){ var fb = document.createElement('script'); fb.type = 'text/javascript'; fb.src = 'https://getfirebug.com/firebug-lite.js#startOpened'; document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0].appendChild(fb); })();</textarea></li>
<li>Go back to your bookmarks, tap the “Edit" button, and select the bookmark you created in Step 2. Tap the url field for that bookmark to edit it. Tap and hold and select all of the old url. Delete. Tap and hold and paste in the javascript.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://galori.github.com/images/firebug_lite_ipad.png" style="border: none; box-shadow: none;"></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why w3schools is bad for the internet]]></title>
    <link href="http://galori.github.com/blog/2013/07/21/why-w3schools-is-bad-for-the-internet/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-21T23:07:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://galori.github.com/blog/2013/07/21/why-w3schools-is-bad-for-the-internet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is quite an old topic, but I've never posted about it and do agree strongly with it.</p>

<p>W3Schools.com is not great. It has outdated information. It does not allow the community to submit corrections. It is not affiliated with the W3C but the name makes it seems like it does, and it has not dis-affiliated itself even after repeated requests from the W3C to do so. It provides outdated, misleading or just plain wrong information to new developers.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Worst of all, it has some great rankings in search engines just by virtue of the fact that it has been around for so long.</p>

<p>There was a concerted grassroots SEO effort by the web development community to dethrone it from its top ranking a few years ago, but it was not successful. See <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=23Yxji-tEfc">Chris Williams talk from JSConf EU 2010</a>.</p>

<p>However, that doesn't mean we can't do anything about it!</p>

<p>What you can do:</p>

<ul>
<li>If you search for any reference material, add "MDN" to your search query to cause the Mozilla Developer Network pages to bubble to the top. For example, instead of "block element", search for "block element mdn". See the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/">MDN</a></li>
<li>If you see someone else linking to W3Schools, tell them! Send them to w3fools.com</li>
<li>Links to MDN from your web site to help their rankings. (This was the goal of the PromoteJS campaign, its still a great idea).</li>
</ul>


<p>For more info, check out the <a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/">W3Fools.com</a> site, also dedicated to this topic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Remember Firebug Lite?]]></title>
    <link href="http://galori.github.com/blog/2013/07/19/remember-firebug-lite/"/>
    <updated>2013-07-19T14:37:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://galori.github.com/blog/2013/07/19/remember-firebug-lite</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>update:</strong> Thanks Joel Moss for linking to this. If you're here, also be sure to check out, <a href="http://gal.steinitz.com/blog/2013/07/22/firebug-lite-on-an-ipad/">Firebug Lite on an iPad</a></p>

<center>
<a href="http://gal.steinitz.com/blog/2013/07/22/firebug-lite-on-an-ipad/"><img src="http://galori.github.com/images/firebug_lite_ipad.png" width="300px"></a>
</center>


<p><strong>Interested in contributing to an open source project but don't know where to start?</strong></p>

<p>I've recently taken over maintaining the Firebug Lite open source project, after it has been abandoned &amp; dormant for 2 years. I have a great fondness for this little bookmarklet that wont stop giving, it has saved me countless times over the years.</p>

<p>I believe it still has some great potential and uses, especially for mobile devices; and of course its always a life saver for older browsers.</p>

<p>If you are interested in pitching in, you could help with Firebug Lit'es web page, the build process, the issues list or the codebase itself.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><em>Firebug Lite's web site</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Overhauling the "Install Firebug Lite" page, including adding an iPad / mobile installation instructions page for the bookmarklet, but also overall simplifying it the whole page. (Also its got mad Javascript errors right now - probably doesn't need 90% of the javascript on that page.)</li>
<li>Migrating all open issues from Google Code to Github (there are some scripts for this). I already migrate the code.</li>
<li>Cleaning up the issues list - are they still relevant, reproduce-able, are they solvable? Perhaps even comment and communicate with the submitter.</li>
<li>Adding Google Analytics event tracking code and server side tracking so we can understand how people are using the bookmarklet.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Build related</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Some "forensic analysis" to reconstruct the build process. I found some remnants of what may have been an ANT script...but the actual script is nowhere to be found (Just like the guy that used to maintain this project). Mainly involves concatenting and then minifying many javascript files and then pushing them to the web site. (Rake, anyone?)</li>
</ul>


<p><em>Dev Related</em></p>

<ul>
<li>Once we figure out the build process...I do have a patch ready to go for one of the outstanding bugs - lets do a new point release! The community will rejoice! (Or at least the 1 guy that submitted it)</li>
<li>Attempt to tackle any of the open issues</li>
<li>Make it work sanely on an iphone/android phone</li>
<li>The top voted issue is actually a security limitation; Where the CSS can not be read if it is being served from a different hostname. More and more common these days with CDN's, etc. Firebug Lite without the CSS rules is kind of useless! A proposed workaround is the classic cross domain ajax fallback - use a server side proxy. Could work - just needs to be implemented.</li>
<li>This project is based on the regular Firebug plugin extension and its libraries. We should try to bring in some of the newer featuers that make sense.</li>
<li>We would kind-of have free reign to modernize this project to keep it relevant. Another idea I had was to provide an automatic proxy for mobile devices, so you would just visit http://getfirebug.com/lite/www.yoursite.com it would just serve your site with the firebug javascript injected - no clunky installing of bookmarks needed.</li>
</ul>


<p>Anyway, if you're interested, reply here, or post to the Firebug Working Group google group, or you can email me at gal (at) steinitz (dot) com.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Global javascript events with Backbone JS]]></title>
    <link href="http://galori.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/global-javascript-events-with-backbone-js/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T20:45:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://galori.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/global-javascript-events-with-backbone-js</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the past I leveraged jQuery's events to create a client side message bus in javascript. Triggering and subscribing to global events is a great way to decouple your javascript code and make it more flexible and maintainable. Enter backbone JS, which has even better built in support for events. An easy way to get started is to bolt on event support to your main global app object:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><code>javascript
_.extend(app,Backbone.Events);
</code></p>

<p>Now you can trigger and subscribe to arbitrary events on your app object. For example if the user can select a twitter stream and your page has various components that change accordingly based on the selected stream: When the stream is selected, trigger the event:</p>

<p><code>javascript
app.trigger('stream-selected',streamName);
</code></p>

<p>Other parts of the code can listen to this event and do something:</p>

<p>``` javascript
app.on('stream-selected',handleStreamSelected);</p>

<p>handleStreamSelected: function(streamName) {
  // do something
}
```</p>

<p>I used this pattern extensively for this <a href="http://events.current.com">Social Dashboard</a> project.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
